Saraba chikyuu yo, tabidatsu fune wa
Farewell Earth, a ship is taking off
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
A New Voyage
Space Battleship
Ucyuu no kanata Iskandar he unmei seoi ima tobitatsu
It's about to take off to Iscandar carrying the fate of humanity
Kanarazu koko he kaette kuru to
We'll return for sure
Te wo furu hito ni egao de kotae
Smile back at the people waving their hands
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Is that the enemy's main fortress ?
Garmillas...
That's the enemy who destroyed
our mother planet of Garmillas.
I want to entrust the future of Garmillas to you.
You, bearing a heart that recognizes
the meaninglessness of war…
Please, use it to guide our people.
Calling on the Dezariam army’s commander.
You mercilessly destroyed the planet Garmillas.
You've taken a number of lives, and now, you're attempting to take Iscandar away.
We can't overlook this tyranny no matter what.
I demand a meeting between representatives.
Combat is not our intention.
In order to avoid further loss on both sides...
Forgive me, Ranhalt.
No matter how meaningless it may seem,
there are certain things I can't forgive.
Not even the Desler Cannon...
How foolish of you to play around
with wave motion energy…
You don't understand anything,
as you only live in the moment.
What's happening ?
Rising gravitational inclinations
detected at random locations.
At random ?
That huge fortress isn't the center ?
Multiple locations...
...a countless number of them within
a 300,000 km radius of Iscandar.
Evasive maneuvers !
Steady !
Gravitational waves are colliding.
Each ship escape at its own discretion.
I'm falling !
Hold my hand...
Their radial gravity can move planets freely.
Once we're caught, we're done for !
Abominable planet Iscandar...
That accursed power of yours must be
placed in the care of Us – Dezariam.
You're unworthy of such power.
You play around with it mindlessly, which will lead to the total destruction of the universe.
This no longer concerns you…so leave.
There's nothing you people can do.
Let Dezariam "tune" everything.
To the Yamato crew...
Führer Desler...
Looks like I underestimated
our enemy's strength.
We'd better withdraw,
so we can get back on track.
Follow me.
What's with him ?
He shot without warning...
That's his way of apologizing.
Earth and Garmillas have shared a growing number of technologies since the security agreement was signed 5 years ago, but...
Yamato has taken quite a lot of damage,
so the situation is dire.
How could Captain Kodai be so reckless ?
You were watching him, right ?
We're all in this together !
That's what all of us decided that day !
So why are you...
Hey, Domon...
Everyone's hungry.
Make the rounds quickly.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Hirata...
“We're all in this together”...
What’s that all about ?
Iscandar is being towed by the enemy fortress,
and it's accelerating toward the star called Bolzon.
If they destroy it in place of the lost planet,
they can transport Iscandar by warping.
I believe that's our enemy's objective.
If we let them get away again, there's no
guarantee we'll be able to catch them.
We should avoid further combat and
prioritize the rescue of everyone on Iscandar.
Slow down.
I do understand the situation.
So, what's your rescue plan ?
As Iscandar approaches the star, the atmospheric temperature is rapidly rising, causing the frozen part of the ocean to melt.
If the situation continues, it'll create a chance to rescue the migrant fleet, which is stranded in the ocean.
Combined with your Garmillan
technology, we can pull this off for sure.
I see.
Then, what's left is the rescue
of the Iscandar royalty, but...
Queen Starsha's resolve
to remain on the planet is firm.
Captain Kodai, can I ask you
to persuade Queen Starsha ?
Your brother, Kodai Mamoru, had a
tremendous impact on Queen Starsha.
If you ask...
No.
I broke the promise with the
very person who saved him...
...and used the wave motion
gun right before her eyes.
I don't think Queen Starsha will listen to me.
But even Queen Starsha understood...
She had to.
I forced her to bend Iscandar's principles
and made her betray her heart.
I believe Führer Desler is the
right person to persuade...
Kodai, why did you come all the way here ?
To save us ?
Or to run away ?
I understand the plan.
I appreciate the kindness of the
Earth from the bottom of my heart.
I request your continued support
in order to save the people of Garmillas.
It's become apparent that
the future Ranhalt bequeathed…
...was entrusted to a small-minded man.
The survivor list isn't complete.
Don't feel so down, okay ?
Lieutenant...
We're the key to this operation.
You'll take Bofen's place since he's wounded.
Alright.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.
I'll command the second ship well.
Yabu...
...I have no words of comfort...
...but never lose hope.
Right. I'll return to the Yamato.
Mœlders, I've been informed
that you've lost Daeder.
Yes.
I sense fluctuations.
Fluctuations deep in your soul.
I'll make amends at once.
No need to panic.
Such fluctuations are proof that Dezariam's
thousand-year dream is not some mere fantasy.
Try to control it.
Don't push those detestable ones away,
rather, take them in or win them over.
That will make us more complete.
We, the light side, are paired
with Iscandar, the dark side.
Make haste.
Looks like they're waiting for someone.
Not just his own citizens...
...Desler will surely seek to save us too.
That's the nature of Garmillas...
...because we "cultivated" them that way.
Leave me alone.
But have some water at least.
What's the point of living through this ?
Garmillas is already...
We have the planet Galman.
That place...
Leave him alone.
You don't understand how we feel.
Why not ?
Is it because I'm a Zaltz ?
Is it because I'm not a native Garmillan ?
Garmillas invaded and brought
ruin to your homeland.
Our turn has come.
It's painful to see your dedication.
It's like we're forced to pay our dues.
What's that got to do with it ?!
I have two fathers...
...one Garmillan, the other Zaltz !
Two fathers !
It doesn't matter where I was born !
I’ve received love, lots of love !
I want to repay the favor
no matter how small it is.
I...
It doesn't matter, huh...
...where you're born,
or where you grow up...?
Mr. Baren !
You used to be in the military, right ?
We received an encrypted military message.
Do you think you can decode it ?
Fellow citizens of Garmillas, the time has come to escape.
This is a race against time.
Implement the following instructions immediately.
Assess the damage to each ship once again.
Abandon non-airtight ships.
Hide in the mist and act quickly.
Fear not.
Enemy eyes will not think to look down.
Unlike the big ones, we can sink
these with a certain number of hits.
Why couldn’t they just transport me
straight into the belly of these big ships ?
The SMITE system's not
that convenient, you know ?
Here they come.
Let's go !
How pointless...
Synchronize all ships.
Let's start with five.
Roger !
Launch decoys ! Don't screw up !
It's time for the first group to arrive.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
It's a success, Captain !
Fellow citizens, don't give up.
Don't accept fate.
In our new land on planet Galman...
...we'll survive.
Hell yeah !
All ships, maintain synchronization and begin to dive.
What's that ?
Where's this light coming from ? Report !
All ships, abort diving and fan out.
Recon alert.
Tell the migrant ships to spread out.
Roger.
Engine output's flatlined !
It’s not responding !
What the hell's going on...?
Damn. Just calm down.
What's that ?
That should be the last noise.
I was careless for not predicting their
practical use of their dimensional dive.
However, the method of detection and capture of a submerged ship shouldn't exist in this space-time.
This marks the end.
Powerful energy detected at the enemy fortress !
It's changing course to aim at...
...the migrant fleet on the sea !
What about Asuka's shield projectile ?
No time ! It's too far !
Captain, the wave motion gun ?
No use !
Even the Desler cannon didn't work !
But...
The wave motion shield...
Sit in the line of fire and deploy the
wave motion shield at maximum output.
That should at least deflect the attack.
But will the Yamato hold ?
Is there any other choice ?!
We're all in this together, right ?!
Deploy the Geshtam wall and follow the Yamato.
Wave motion shield output has dropped to 23% !
It's powering up for a second shot.
Stop this !
Starsha...
No more fighting.
I know what you want.
I'll ask the commanders of the
Earth and Garmillas forces to leave.
Give me a little time.
If I don't ?
You won't get what you want.
It's time to tell you the truth...
...the truth about the blue blood of Garmillas.
Truth...?
Commanders of both forces,
come to the Crystal Palace.
I'll be waiting.
Immigrant Fleet Rescue Operation. Go Beyond the Dimensional Wall!
Episode 6
Iscandar, the Dying Planet of Sorrow
Next Time
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Ryusuke Domon:
Shigeru Sakamoto:
Tasuke Tokugawa:
Akira Yamamoto:
Kaoru Niimi:
Yasuo Nanbu:
Susumu Yamazaki:
Miki Saijo:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Mikage Kiryuu:
Hajime Hirata:
Sho Sawamura:
Hiroki Shinohara:
Nishina:
Analyzers:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Tasuku Hatanaka
Kento Ito
Nobuhiko Okamoto
Rie Tanaka
Aya Hisakawa
Kenji Akabane
Hiroshi Tsuchida
Satomi Moriya
Ryuichi Kijima
Eriko Nakamura
Fumihide Ise
Yuya Chikaki
Daisuke Hirakawa
Kenta Miyake
Cho
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Wolf Flaken:
Gol Heini:
Melda Dietz:
Yabu Sukelji:
Hilde Shultz:
Vance Baren:
Koichi Yamadera
Hiroshi Kamiya
Akimitsu Takase
Setsuji Sato
Shizuka Ito
Cho
Ayano Miura
Shinya Fukumatsu
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Mœlders:
Woman's Voice:
Crew A:
Crew B:
Crew C:
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Takaya Kuroda
Keiko Han
Takahiro Ayase
Keisuke Hamaoka
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru